# Oscar Hernandez Baute

**Computer Engineering** 

+1 786 827 8028

Miami, Florida oscarhernandezbaute@gmail.com

https://oscarhdezbaute.github.io/

linkedin.com/in/oscar-hernandez-baute-b13007317

SUMMARY Computer engineering, full stack .NET developer with more than 14 years of experience in C# & .NET technologies and frameworks. Also experience in working with SCADA, HMI, PLC and DCS programming. With teamwork and freelance skills with high work performance and years of general experience in the industry. Experience including requirements gathering, design, coding, testing, debugging and maintenance.

### **EDUCATION**

## **Computer Engineering**

University of Cienfuegos "Carlos Rafael Rodríguez" | 2003 - 2008, Cienfuegos, Cuba.

#### EXPERIENCE

#### Florida IT Solutions

## Senior Software Engineer | December 2023 - Ongoing | Remote

- Analysis of requirements with clients in the health sectors.
- Design, development and testing of applications back-end and front-end using .NET CORE, Entity Framework (EF) Core, Asp.NET, C#, Asp.NET Web Api, MVC, Blazor.
- Technical support to clients.

#### **CEDAI Inc - Industrial Automation**

## Senior Specialist in IT, Communications and Automation | Dec 2012 - Dec 2023

- Analysis of requirements with clients in the industrial, financial and health sectors.
- Design, development and testing of several applications back-end and front-end in the sectors mentioned above, using Asp.NET, C#, NET CORE, MVC, WebForms, Blazor, Xamarin Forms, WinForms. EF, Nhibernate, API, RESTful Service.
- Front-end & back-end applications maintenance.
- Technical support to clients, experience with continuous integration and continuous delivery.
- PLC programming with SIEMENS and Schneider Electric technology.
- HMI & SCADA design with SIEMENS and Schneider Electric technology.
- Design and programming DCS Centum VP Yokogawa.
- Design, installation and operation of industrial communication networks: MODBUS RTU, MODBUS TCP/IP, MPI, PROFIBUS DP, PROFINET.
- Set up of starters, Variable Frequency Drives and intelligent motor controllers, with manufacturers like SIEMENS, and Schneider Electric.

## **CEDAI Inc - Industrial Automation**

## Junior Specialist in IT, Communications and Automation | Dec 2008 - Nov 2012

- PLC programming with SIEMENS and Automation Direct technology.
- HMI & SCADA design with SIEMENS technology.
- Wiring of electrical panelboards for industrial applications.
- Front-end and back-end applications developer, Javascript, HTML5. C#, Net Framework 3.5, 4.0 Asp.NET WebForms, Winforms, Razor, jQuery, NHibernate, SQL Server.
- Data transport structures such as JSON, XML.
- Desktop & web applications maintenance.

## ABILITIES

C# | C++ | ASP.NET | NET CORE | MVC | Entity framework | NHibernate | ADO.NET | Blazor | WebForms | WinForms | Xamarin Forms | REST | API | XML | XAML | HTML | JSON | Javascript | Boostrap | jQuery | CSS | SQL Server | Transact-SQL | Stored procedures | MySQL | RUP | UML | XP methodology | GIT | Azure DevOps SCADA | PLC programming | OPC | Tia Portal | WinCC | SIMATIC STEP 7 | MicroWin | WinCC Flexible | PROFIBUS | MODBUS TCP/IP | MODBUS RTU | PROFINET | SoMachine

Spanish: Native English: Intermediate LANGUAGES